Guide to the Cornwall Miscellanea 1779-2003 MS 011 MS 011 MS 011
Cornwall Historical Society
- Photographic Materials
  - Photographs
    - Locations
      - West Cornwall
        - Covered Bridge: Interior Views, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 3)
          Photographs of the interior of the West Cornwall Covered Bridge taken by Don Henry.
        - Covered Bridge: Repairs, 2000, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 4)
          Photographs of maintenance work done on the West Cornwall Covered Bridge.
        - Covered Bridge: Repairs Part II, 2000, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 5)
        - Covered Bridge Building and Hardware, 1942-1978, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 6)
          Photographs of Covered Bridge Building and Hardware, a business that operated out of the building currently occupied by Covered Bridge Pottery. Images include photos of the interior and exterior of the store as well as a group photo of Fitz Bruhel, Catherine Palmer, Al Storrs, and C.S. Smith.
        - Housatonic River: Part I, circa 1880-1924, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 7)
          Nineteenth-century photographs of the Housatonic River. There are images of the surrounding countryside and of the dam built by the Mallinson shear shop.
          - Housatonic River, N.D. (Box OS 3, Folder 2)
            Reproduced photos of the Housatonic River, including images of the "old dam" belonging to the Mallinson company.
          - Housatonic River, 1924 (Box OS 3, Folder 22)
            Photograph of the Housatonic River taken by George H. Beck.
        - Housatonic River: Part II, 1973-1976, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 8)
          Photographs of people taking part in various recreational activities along the Housatonic River. There are images of kayakers and fisherman, and and of picnickers surveying the wreckage of the "Kaolin Bridge."
        - Housatonic River: Part III, circa 1930-1989, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 9)
          Photographs of the Housatonic River taken during the twentieth century, as well as modern reproductions of older images. There are images of the river and the surrounding area and of the dam from the Mallinson shear shop.
        - Train Station, 1927-circa 2000, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 10)
          Photographs of the West Cornwall Train Station. Photos include images of the station, trains, and passengers.
        - Train Station Plaza, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 11)
          Photographs of the plaza near the railroad station. Specific images include photos of a hardware store, decorating shop, studio, and dress shop. One photo is addressed to Hattie Sandmeyer from Edna Beck.
        - Landscapes, circa 1920-circa 1934 (Box 22, Folder 12)
          Photographs of various landscapes in West Cornwall. Specific images include a view from Dibble Hill and a photo of the hill behind Yutzler's store.
        - Brown's Package Store/ The Wandering Moose (Box 22, Folder 13)
          Photographs of the building at the corner of Route 128 and Lower River Road. The building, formerly known as "The Emporium," has housed businesses such as Brown's Package Store and the Wandering Moose.
        - Frank Whitney House, September 1942 (Box 22, Folder 14)
          Photographs of the home formerly owned by Frank Whitney, located on "Fog Alley."
        - Bishop Bungalow, 1927-1942, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 15)
          Photograph of the bungalow first owned by E.G. Bishop, and then later by the Richardson family. The home stood near "the bend" of the Housatonic River, but is no longer extant.
        - Townscapes, circa 1860-1976, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 16)
          Photographs of the village of West Cornwall taken from various high elevations. There are photos taken from the Sharon side of the Housatonic River and from within West Cornwall itself.
        - Views of Main Street, circa 1910-1995 (Box 22, Folder 17)
          Photographs of the section of Route 128 that passes through the village of West Cornwall. Photos include images of the road itself, as well as various homes and businesses along its route. Specific images include photos of The Deck, Brookside Bistro, the old West Cornwall Fire House, and the Joe Lush House.
        - Sharon-Goshen Turnpike/ Route 128, 1940-circa 2000, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 18)
          Photographs of Route 128 outside the bounds of the village of West Cornwall. Photos include both images of the road itself, as well as structures along its route. Specified buildings include the Billbee Hills Farm, the Terhune House, and a home owned by George Dibble, and then later by Phil Bishop.
        - Former Roman Catholic Church, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 19)
          Photographs of the building formerly used as a Roman Catholic Church in West Cornwall. The parish later moved to St. Bridget's Church in Cornwall Bridge and the building is currently owned by Bain Real Estate.
        - Toll House, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 20)
          Photographs of the old toll house near the West Cornwall Covered Bridge. The building currently houses Ian Ingersoll Cabinetmakers.
        - Bookstore, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 21)
          Photographs of the bookstore in West Cornwall. The shop was owned by Martin and Gold at one time, and is currently operated by Barbara Farnsworth.
        - Mansion House, 1924, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 22)
          Photographs of the Mansion House Hotel. The building stood near the site of the current post office and was destroyed by fire in November 1924. Photos include images of the building during its heyday and the aftermath of the fire.
        - Trinity Conference Center, 1996-2004, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 23)
          Photographs of the Trinity Conference Center on Lower River Road. One photo shows Wendy and John Denn, managers of the property, and another depicts the building known as "Yellow Camp" that was once the home of Joseph Mallinson, founder of the shear-making company that was located nearby.
        - Unlabeled Buildings, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 24)
          Photographs of various unlabeled buildings in West Cornwall.
        - Old Masonic Hall, 1975, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 25)
          Photographs of the former Masonic Hall in West Cornwall. The building was built in 1901 and later housed the business of Martin and Gold and Barbara Farnsworth.
        - Cornwall Bridge Pottery/ Smith and Sons, 1989, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 26)
          Photographs of the multipurpose building in West Cornwall just to the east of the railroad tracks. The building was constructed in the mid-nineteenth century and originally functioned as a general store run by Pratt and Foster. Photos depict the business when it was operated by Smith and Sons and by Cornwall Bridge Pottery.
          - Cornwall Bridge Pottery Album: Part I, N.D. (Box OS 3, Folder 4)
            The first part of a photo album showing the work down at the Cornwall Bridge Pottery.
          - Cornwall Bridge Pottery Album: Part II, N.D. (Box OS 3, Folder 5)
            The second section of a photo album devoted to Cornwall Bridge Pottery.
          - Cornwall Bridge Pottery Album: Part III, N.D. (Box OS 3, Folder 6)
            The final part of a photo album showing the work done at Cornwall Bridge Pottery.
        - Cochrane Brothers, 1989, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 27)
          Photographs of the general store run by Cochrane Brothers. The building later became The Deck restaurant.
          - Cochrane Bros. Store, 1895 (Box OS 3, Folder 7)
            Photograph of people posing in front of the Cochrane Bros. Store.
        - Miscellaneous, circa 1910-circa 1954, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 28)
          Photographs of miscellaneous buildings and events in West Cornwall. Specific images include homes owned by Oliver Hart, Joann Beeman, N. Young, Denny Curtis, Everett Cole, and Mary Smith. There are also photographs of a Standard Oil delivery wagon, the parsonage building, and the pickup truck owned by the D and S Building Co. An image of a frozen water main break is also included.
        - Stereoscopic views of the Foster House, N.D. (Box 33, Folder 34)
          Stereoscopic views of the Foster House in West Cornwall.
        - Stereoscopic views of the Housatonic River, N.D. (Box 33, Folder 35)
          Stereoscopic views of the Housatonic River. Photos include images of the West Cornwall Covered Bridge and the original Mallinson shear-making factory.
        - Stereoscopic views of the Mallinson Shear Shop, N.D. (Box 33, Folder 36)
          Photographs of the Mallinson Shear Shop taken from across the Housatonic River in Sharon.
        - Stereoscopic views of the O'Donnell House, N.D. (Box 33, Folder 37)
          Photographs of the O'Donnell House in West Cornwall.
        - Stereoscopic views of the Yutzler Tailor Shop, N.D. (Box 33, Folder 38)
          Stereoscopic views of the tailor shop in West Cornwall operated by the Yutzler family.
        - Stereoscopic views of the Porter Druggist Staff, N.D. (Box 33, Folder 39)
          Stereoscopic views of the staff from the drug store run by the Porter family.
        - Stereoscopic views of Main Street, N.D. (Box 33, Folder 40)
          Stereoscopic views of Main Street in West Cornwall.
        - Stereoscopic views of River Road, N.D. (Box 34, Folder 1)
          Stereoscopic views of River Road in West Cornwall.
        - Stereoscopic landscape views (Box 34, Folder 2)
          Stereoscopic views of various landscapes in West Cornwall.
        - Stereoscopic views of the District 15 School, N.D. (Box 34, Folder 3)
          Stereoscopic view of the District 15 School, with the teacher and class, on Lower River Road.
        - Covered Bridge, 1973-1996, N.D. (Box 35, Folder 24)
          Assorted black and white photographs of the covered bridge.
        - Rotary, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 32)
          Photograph of the rotary on Main Street.
        - Cartwright House, June 1941 (Box 37, Folder 14)
          Photograph of the Cartwright family home.
        - Fred Bate House, N.D. (Box 37, Folder 14)
          Photograph of the Fred Bate home.
        - Handlin Property, September 1940 (Box 37, Folder 15)
          Photograph of the home owned by Nellie Handlin.
        - Russell Property, August 1941 (Box 37, Folder 16)
          Photograph of the Russell property, across the brook from the Yutzler property.
        - Aerial Survey, 1934 (Box OS 4, Object 1)
          Aerial view of West Cornwall.
      - Miscellaneous
        - Landscapes, circa 1920, N.D. (Box 37, Folder 1)
          Photographs of various Cornwall landscapes, including ice-cutting on Winchell's Pond and the view from the Rexford family home.
        - Unlabeled Cornwall Buildings, 1993, N.D. (Box 37, Folder 2)
          Photographs of unlabeled Cornwall buildings.
        - Non-Cornwall Buildings, 1888-1948, N.D. (Box 37, Folder 3)
          Photographs of non-Cornwall buildings, including the Hartford Trust Company building in Hartford after the Blizzard of 1888, the Stone residence in Warren, the Emmons farm in Morris, and the Palmer house in Goshen.
        - Unidentified Home, N.D. (Box OS 3, Folder 18)
          Photograph of an unidentified home.
    - People
      - Samuel Adams, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 1)
        Photograph of Samuel Adams donated by Mrs. Walter Swan. Adams was deacon in the Cornwall Baptist Church and married to Julia Hurburt. He is buried in West Cornwall.
      - Allen Family, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 2)
        Photograph of Alanson Allen.
      - Ammason Family, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 3)
        Portrait of the Allason family. Members include Anna, Ed, Nellie, Lilian, and Harry Allason.
      - Andrews Family, 1882, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 4)
        Photographs of the Andrews family. Many photos are of John T. Andrews, who lived on Pine Street with his wife Jane Jones Andrews. An image of Jane is also present, along with one of John with his three brothers.
      - Baldwin Family, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 5)
        Photographs of the Cornwall Baldwin family. Specific members depicted are: Reverend Ebenezer Baldwin, T. Robert Baldwin, Edward R. Baldwin, and Professor Edward C. Baldwin.
      - Fred Bate, Jr., N.D. (Box 23, Folder 6)
        Photographs of Fred Bate, Jr. Photos include an image of Bate as a young man in his U.S. Army uniform and later as the honorary grand marshall of a parade.
      - Levi Beebe, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 7)
        Portrait of Levi Beebe, the father of Cornelia Bradford.
      - Beeman Family, 1927-1951 (Box 23, Folder 8)
        Photographs of the Beeman family. In one photo, Sherman Beeman is posing on top of a wagon full of hay, and in the other, Esther R. Beeman is seen reading with a cat.
      - Behn Family, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 9)
        Photographs of the Behn family. The photos show blacksmith Donald Behn at work at his shop in Cornwall Bridge.
      - Benedict Family, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 10)
        Photograph of Dr. Abel Carter Benedict (1837-1898). The Bethel, Conn. native studied medicine at Yale before serving in the Union Army. He is buried in Cornwall.
      - Edna Bragan, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 11)
        Photograph of Edna Bragan posing near a picket fence.
      - Blake Family, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 12)
        Photographs of the Blake family. Images include photos of James Blake (1825-1916), an East Cornwall farmer, and his descendants. Specific descendants include his son Charles and granddaughter Marian. There are also photographs of Eddie Blake, who died after falling out of a school house window, and of Bessie Root Blake shopping in Cochrane's Store.
      - Gerry Blakey, circa 1954, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 13)
        Photographs of Cornwall resident Gerry Blakey.
      - Charles D. Blinn, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 14)
        Photograph of Colonel Charles D. Blinn, who served in the 13th Connecticut Volunteer Regiment during the Civil War.
      - Bradford Family, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 15)
        Photographs of the Bradford family. Specific family members include Fowler Bradford and Charlotte Belden Bradford, Cornelia Bradford, Louisa Bradford Fox, James Fitch Bradford, and John Bradford.
      - Earl Brecher, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 16)
        Polaroid photograph of Earl Brecher.
      - Breen Family, 1886, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 17)
        Photographs of the Breen family. Specific family members include John Breen and William H. Breen, who owned a general store in Cornwall Bridge.
      - Edward Everett Brewster, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 18)
        Portrait of Edward Everett Brewster.
      - Brown Family, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 19)
        Portrait of the Brown family. Specific family members include siblings Quincy Brown, Hattie Brown Humphrey, Abbie Brown Phelps, Mary Lydia Brown Clark, and Lottie Brown.
      - Fritz Bruehl, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 20)
        Photographs of the artist Fritz Bruehl and several of his works. Bruehl was the staff artist at Trinity.
      - Bunnell Family, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 21)
        Photographs of the Bunnell family. Specific family members include Oscar and Bertha Bunnell with their four daughters, and Belle Kellogg Bunnell.
      - G. H. Burgraff, 1904 (Box 23, Folder 22)
        Portrait of G.H. Burgraff.
      - Calhoun Family, circa 1890-1927, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 23)
        Photographs of the Calhoun family. Specific family members include Mr. and Mrs. John E. Calhoun and Jean Calhoun Bacon. Photos also include images of the Calhoun farm in Cornwall Plain, including the farm house, which burnt down in 1911 and was rebuilt in 1912.
        - Glass Plate Negative Family Photographs, N.D. (Box OS 3, Folder 1)
          Glass plate negatives from family photographs of the Calhoun family.
      - Bertie Cartwright, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 24)
        Photograph of Bertie Cartwright walking through West Cornwall.
      - Lillie Catlin, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 25)
        Portrait of Lillie Catlin.
      - Chipman Family, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 26)
        Photographs of life on the Oliver Chipman farm.
      - Harriet L. Clark, circa 1914-1985, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 27)
        Photographs of Harriet L. Clark. Clark was active in both state politics and in the Cornwall Historical Society. Images of Clark include photos of both her political and personal life.
        - Harriet L. Clark with Hooked Rug, N.D. (Box OS 2, Folder 14)
          Photograph of Harriet L. Clark with a prize-winning hooked rug.
        - Harriet L. Clark and Sasha Clark (Box OS 2, Folder 15)
          Photograph of Harriet L. Clark with Sasha Clark.
        - Sasha Clark, N.D. (Box OS 2, Folder 16)
          Close-up photograph of Sasha Clark.
      - Clark Family, 1908-1940, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 28)
        Photographs of the Clark family of East Cornwall. Specific family members include Sheldon Clark, L. Clark, William L. Clark, William B. Clark, Ernest Dwight Clark, Lydia Brown Clark, Loyal Brown Clark, Melissa Clark, and Charlotte Clark.
      - Lottie Clarke, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 29)
        Portrait of Lottie Clark.
      - Cochrane Family, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 30)
        Photographs of the Cochrane family. Specific family members include Miner Cochrane, Jessie Rogers Cochrane, H.G. Cochrane, and J.G. Cochrane.
        - Cochrane Family Portrait, N.D. (Box OS 3, Folder 15)
          Photograph of the Cochrane family posing outside their home in West Cornwall.
      - Henry Cole, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 31)
        Portrait of Henry Cole.
      - Corban Family, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 32)
        Photographs of the Corban family. One image depicts Mryon Corban in a wagon full of hay and the other shows unspecified Corban children posed in front of their home.
        - George Corban, October 1969 (Box OS 2, Folder 17)
          Photograph of George Corban taken by Armin Landeck.
      - Crosby Family, circa 1920, N.D. (Box 23, Folder 33)
        Photographs of the Crosby family. Specific family members are Katherine Salenski Crosby and her husband George Crosby. One series of photos depicts George Crosby building a bookshelf, and another shows a boating trip.
      - Dixon Family, 1894-circa 1915 (Box 23, Folder 34)
        Photographs of Methodist Chaplain Charles Dixon and of Jack Dixon with a team of horses.
      - Elizabeth Dudley Hyde, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 35)
        Photograph of Elizabeth Dudley Hyde (1861-1951). Hyde was the daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Lafayette Dudley, who were Cornwall residents, but she herself spent her life in New York and Ohio.
      - Ellingwood Family, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 1)
        Portrait of the Ellingwood family. Woolsey Ellingwood, Martorie Ellingwood, and John E. Calhoun are shown sitting with Ellingwood grandchildren.
      - Lewis Emmons, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 2)
        Portrait of Lewis Emmons, half-brother of Milton Emmons.
      - Engisch Family, 1919-1932, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 3)
        Photographs of the Engisch family. Photos include Walter Engisch in his military uniform and posed with George Engisch in front of their store in Cornwall Bridge. There are also a collection of personal photos formerly belonging to Mabel Engisch, including images related to her teaching career and of her with Joseph McArthur.
      - Neil Estern, September 1997 (Box 24, Folder 4)
        Photograph of Neil Estern.
      - Ed Ferman, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 5)
        Photograph of Ed Ferman.
      - Foot Family, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 6)
        Photographs of Dr. Edward Foot and his family. Many of the photos depict life on the family farm.
      - Ford Family: Part I, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 7)
        Portraits of members of the extended Ford family. Specified members of the family are Charles Ford, W. Dakin, Dr. and Mrs. W.E. Knibloe, and Will Calendar.
      - Ford Family: Part II, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 8)
        Portraits of extended Ford family members. Specified individuals are Harold Ford, Clinton Goodale, and Leo Dean.
      - Ford Family: Part III, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 9)
        Small portraits of members of the extended Ford family. Identified family members are George W. Ford, Emma Ford, Alice Dakin, Mr. and Mrs. Cole, Mrs. C. E. Baldwin, and Grace Baldwin.
      - Stephen Foster, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 10)
        Portrait of Stephen Foster. Foster was co-owner of the West Cornwall business Pratt and Foster.
      - Gannett Family, April 23, 1966- July 22, 2008, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 11)
        Photographs of the Gannett family. Included in the collection are photos of Lewis and Ruth Gannett, as well as photographs of Michael Gannett.
        - Gannett House, N.D. (Box OS 2, Folder 21)
          Photograph of the Gannett House.
        - Ruth Gannett Garden, N.D. (Box OS 3, Folder 20)
          Photograph of Ruth Gannett's gardens.
      - Gates Family, August 1985, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 12)
        Photographs of Judith Gates and of actor Larry Gates with Rose Algrant.
      - Helen Gazagnaire, August 1976- March 1984, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 13)
        Photographs of Helen Gazagnaire.
      - Jill Gibbons, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 14)
        Photograph of Jill Gibbons.
      - Gold Family, 1906-1908, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 15)
        Photographs of the Gold family. Specific members include Thedore S. Gold, S.W. Gold, Phebe C. Gold, Samuel F. Gold of New Jersey, Egbert H. Gold of Chicago.
      - Florance Gomez, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 16)
        Photograph of Florance Gomez.
      - Robert Graham, circa 1990 (Box 24, Folder 17)
        Photographs of Robert Graham dousing for water in Dudleytown.
      - Leila Beatrice Gregory, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 18)
        Portrait of Leila Beatrice Gregory at age three.
      - Hallock Family, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 19)
        Portrait of two Hallock children.
      - Harrison Family, 1870-1913, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 20)
        Photographs of the Harrison family. There is a series of photos depicting the family of George Chandler Harrison (1840-1907) at their home, Plainview, taken from 1911-1913. There are also photos of Marian Louise Harrison, John R. Harrison, Eleanor Bradford Harrison, Myron Harrison, and a portrait of George Chandler Harrison during his time as a state legislator.
      - Hart Family: Part I, 1908, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 21)
        Photographs of the Hart family. One collection of photos is from the "Hart Calendar" and shows scenes from the Hart farm. Other photos include portraits of Rev. John Clark Hart, E. Burton Hart, and Rep. Nathan Hart, as well as a portrait of Oliver, Betsy, and Martha Hart.
      - Hart Family: Part II, 1883-circa 1940, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 22)
        Photographs of the Hart family. Photos include a portrait of Charles and Nellie Hart, a group photograph of the Hart, Hedden, and O'Donnell families, as well as images of Doug Hart, Ethel and Olive Hart, Leroy Hart, Wallace Hart, Amy Hart, Oliver Hart, and Alden Hart.
      - Maureen Hawes, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 23)
        Photograph of Maureen Hawes.
      - Hewett Family, circa 1890, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 24)
        Photographs of the Hewett family. Photos include a portrait of Mary Hewett, Harrison Hewett,and Kate Harrison Hewett sitting on their front porch, and images of Kate Harrison Hewett at her spinning wheel.
      - Reverend Hoppin (Box 24, Folder 25)
        Portrait of Reverend Hoppin, pastor of the North Cornwall Meeting House.
      - Abner A. Horner, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 26)
        Photograph of Abner A. Horner sitting in his study. Horner was a member of the Lafayette College Class of 1911.
      - Ives Family, 1893, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 27)
        Photographs of the Ives family. Images include photos of the Ives family farm copied from the photo album of Lucy Ives, as well as a portrait of Lucy May Ives as an infant.
      - James Family, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 28)
        Portraits of Mr. and Mrs. Almon James.
      - Judson Family, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 29)
        Photographs of the Judson family. Images include a photo of Lillian Beach, Mrs. Judson, Mrs. Jessop, and Mary Jessop Beach. There is also a photo showing the interior of the Judson home.